Professor Wilson was one of the first scientists to explore this area
威尔逊教授是最早探索该地区的科学家之一
together with local wildlife biologist Tonga Tortuda.
同行的还有当地野生生物学家唐加·托奇塔
If you could gather them all up,
如果你可以把他们都聚在一起
all these little invertebrate creatures, and weigh them,
那些小小的无脊椎动物  然后称下重量
they would weigh far more
他们可能
than all of the big animals put together,
比这里所有的大型动物加起来还要重
even in a fully restored park.
即使是在一个生态完全恢复的公园里
It's these little creatures, together with the plants and trees,
正是这些小小的生物  还有植物
that still make this place
使这个地方
a viable option for reintroducing bigger animals.
成为重新引进大型动物的可选之地
I can't be sure that's a new species,
我不确定这是个新物种
but this is the kind of thing that might be.
但很有可能是的
This park came that close to vanishing...
这个公园几乎就要消失了
..And I'm happy to report it is coming back.
我非常高兴地宣布它复苏了
And this is one of the great stories.
这是一个伟大的故事
It's inspirational, I think.
我觉得真是鼓舞人心
It's a fine, shining example of what to do with all our parks,
这是我们挽救公园的光辉案例
even those that have been damaged by human activity.
即使是那些曾被人类活动所破坏过的
But there's another reason why Gorongosa is important
但还有另外一个原因决定了戈龙戈萨为何
for the future of Africa and perhaps for us all.
对非洲  甚至对我们全人类都很重要
It is here, in this park,
正是在这里  这个公园
that people come to see, not just the big animals that thrill us,
人们不仅可以看到那些令我们震撼的大型动物
but they will see Earth as it looked and felt
也能看到人类诞生之前
before the coming of humanity.
地球的原貌
Saving big animals is important,
拯救大型动物很重要
but to do that with any real success,
但是要想成功
we have to start understanding and preserving the plants
我们必须理解和保护
and insects that support an ecosystem.
那些支持生态系统的植物与昆虫
It's this that will allow the larger animals to thrive.
只有这样才能让大型动物生生不息